[{"id": "5fbaed870738315b1fb74e30", "question": "What spell was used to trick the Goblet in \"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\"?", "answer": "Confundus Charm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c7c6fbde8045e48466c7", "question": "What is the space between your nostrils called?", "answer": "Columella nasi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba18", "question": "What does the abbreviation NASA stand for?", "answer": "National Aeronautics and Space Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa9596ce05a3942286ee0", "question": "What was the name of the Lone Ranger\u2019s horse?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea8136ff048f679a45ac1e", "question": "What disorder often leads to sufferers eating odd items such as dirt or metal?", "answer": "Pica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8be1ec223966ae8f8844", "question": "Which television series revolves around a concierge doctor making house calls in the Hamptons?", "answer": "\"Royal Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a66", "question": "What was the name of the short-lived 2002 sitcom which starred Andy Richter in the title role?", "answer": "Andy Richter Controls the Universe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e72", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Butterflies Are Free\"?", "answer": "Edward Albert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde3", "question": "What's the shortest standard reply on a Magic 8-Ball?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e475fe83fe1f2a824bb4", "question": "Which Allied country\u2019s forces arrived in Berlin first?", "answer": "USSR's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0a", "question": "What year did Anna Nicole Smith die from a drug overdose?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a7f6096f5f79087132fb42", "question": "In finance, what does \"QRM\" stand for?", "answer": "Quantitative Risk Management", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0df", "question": "Which pasta has a wide-ringed shape?", "answer": "Calamarata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e39", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The Old Sea-dog at the Admiral Benbow\"?", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb6e065ff7d326b622a9b", "question": "Which baseball player was nicknamed \"The Bambino\"?", "answer": "Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d8", "question": "What moisturizer is derived from sheep's wool?", "answer": "Lanolin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc7", "question": "Taal is an alternative name for what language?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f3", "question": "Whose remains were thrown into the Seine River on May 30, 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a128", "question": "What band got their name from the 1960's film \"Barbarella\"?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cd", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Unconditional Surrender\"?", "answer": "Ulysses S. Grant", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a136", "question": "What film starred Helen Hunt, Cary Elwes and Bill Paxton?", "answer": "Twister", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133986a", "question": "In Disney's \"Cinderella\", what is the cats name?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff0", "question": "Which US president delivered the Gettysburg Address?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be49", "question": "What is Port Salut?", "answer": "A type of cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffe4ae447818f5674af01af", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I am one of the few honest people I have ever known\".?", "answer": "\"The Great Gatsby\" (Nick Carraway, a main character and the narrator of the famous novel says this line early on in the story.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d4", "question": "In what US state would you find Area 51?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ba", "question": "What city is home to the headquarters of the Boeing Company?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339669", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaee2c0738315b1fb74e32", "question": "Who are Quagmire\u2019s daughters in the TV show \"Family Guy\"", "answer": "Anna Lee and Courtney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99cd621a8909e5c332d3b", "question": "What is the capita of Corsica?", "answer": "Ajaccio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73eeeeec85e375820b276", "question": "Which state's tree is the American Holly?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b322", "question": "What Asian leader was known as the \"little brown saint\"?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e804ffde59ea584496fea8", "question": "Archie Moore is typically associated with which sport?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903b", "question": "Which musical term denotes that a piece is to be played \"sweetly\"?", "answer": "Dolce", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b246", "question": "The US's first law school for women was named for what cross-dressing Shakespearean character?", "answer": "Portia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d47071f8e329de4f877891", "question": "What year was cricketer Phil Tufnell born?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22a", "question": "Whittaker Chambers hid Alger Hiss' purloined State Department documents in a hollowed-out what?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a44", "question": "What dance craze inspired the 1990 film \"The Forbidden Dance\"?", "answer": "The lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b491e49076251badbeaac", "question": "Who said, \"In the future, everyone will be world-famous for 15 minutes\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol -- There is debate as to whether the phrase is his word, but branded it and put in pamphlet in 1968.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a754", "question": "Which four US states begin with the word \"New\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico and New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd0", "question": "In what ominous numbered room is Winston Smith strapped to a chair at the end of \"Nineteen Eighty-Four\"?", "answer": "Room 101", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017403344491cbd7c5a17bc", "question": "When was the Soviet Union (U.S.S.R.) formed?", "answer": "December 30, 1922", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dde", "question": "What two British politicians of the 1960s are mentioned by George Harrison in \"Taxman\"?", "answer": "Harold Wilson and Edward Heath", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c5", "question": "Whose military textbook \"Infantry Attacks\" was read, famously by George Patton?", "answer": "Erwin Rommel's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571c2367df192a942e3371", "question": "What is the capital of Togo?", "answer": "Lome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d5722b42d4a3561a9f02", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what does Darcy Parker tattoo on the right breast of her lovers?", "answer": "A rose", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f1", "question": "What chemical element has been added to table salt since 1924, to help prevent goiter?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb1be8df497e33de8057918", "question": "Who scored the first counted three-point basket in NBA history?", "answer": "Chris Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c198", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a501", "question": "Which side of Niagara Falls has the largest falls - the US or Canadian side?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a552b23e1c6f9840ba319b", "question": "Which country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2c", "question": "Who served as President of the US from 1933 to 1945?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ac", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a9", "question": "Myopia is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Nearsightedness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d0", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was rich on Monday but broke on Sunday?", "answer": "Solomon Grundy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fb", "question": "In the 1998 movie \"You've Got Mail\", Joe and Kelly are in what business?", "answer": "Book retailing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339579", "question": "In A Christmas Carol what song is sung outside of Scrooge's office?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f2", "question": "What US state has been governed by Evan Mecham and Bruce Babbitt?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5901d8c7709c1c34536e6ea7", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c935", "question": "What is an Otoscope used to look at?", "answer": "The Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb5", "question": "What rock star caused a stir in 2007 when he said that he'd snorted his late father's cremains?", "answer": "Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389af", "question": "Whose wife was turned into a pillar of salt?", "answer": "Lot's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ac", "question": "What nation was led by Frederick the Great?", "answer": "Prussia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49f", "question": "Which country were the 1920 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56a", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for the state of Virginia?", "answer": "VA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b79", "question": "What instrument did Teddy Wilson play in the Benny Goodman Swing Quartet?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a434", "question": "Which tribes are native to New Zealand?", "answer": "Maori", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f0", "question": "In which US state was rapper \"Eminem\" born?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b14", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b803e662d71a5365101b", "question": "The Semper Opera House is located where?", "answer": "Dresden, Germany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cefc0c4948005ec986edcdf", "question": "Who is the sixth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Kim Lip", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a69", "question": "The line \"I never saw a purple cow\" is the beginning of a poem by what author?", "answer": "Gelett Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339556", "question": "For what film did Liza Minnelli win the Academy Award for Best Leading Actress?", "answer": "Cabaret", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25b", "question": "Which English county was Alfred Hitchcock born in?", "answer": "Essex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b39", "question": "What Clint Eastwood film was loosely inspired by the 1960's serial killer known as the Zodiac Killer?", "answer": "Dirty Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9d", "question": "What bathroom cleaner was originally advertised by the Scrubbing Bubbles?", "answer": "Dow bathroom cleaner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fe82a4edfd43a087adcf", "question": "What does a ventriloquist typically hold on their lap?", "answer": "A puppet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3f12d8b5801b8f54a7fbe", "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague\u2019s astronomical clock?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb84", "question": "How long, in feet, is the Brooklyn Bridge?", "answer": "5,989 ft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca79", "question": "What is the Latin word for the beech tree?", "answer": "Fagus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a551", "question": "The San Andreas Fault is located in which state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefb", "question": "What American outlaw went by such names as Kid Antrim, Henry McCarty and William Bonney?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933d", "question": "How many years did the TV show \"I Love Lucy\" run for?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d9b3908b8581f80b092c3", "question": "What three gaming consoles did Nintendo release in 2017?", "answer": "Nintendo Switch, New Nintendo 2DS XL, and Super NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b4", "question": "Maria Sklodowska became famous under what name?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600395b157a0e35c43f83895", "question": "What prompted Pablo Picasso's famous Blue Period?", "answer": "This period was an artistic response to his depression over the death of Carlos Casagemas,\u00a0a friend who shot himself.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fb", "question": "Who wrote the 1994 novel \"The Fist of God\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d35", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of The Green Berets\"?", "answer": "Barry Sadler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5b8d6ce05a3942286e17", "question": "Frank Sinatra rewrote \"High Hopes\" for what president's campaign?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1eca1145fb29466707387", "question": "What does the Qantas airline name stand for?", "answer": "Queensland and Northern Territory Aerial Services", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56c", "question": "Phobos is the name of one of the moons of which planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bf", "question": "Yellowstone Lake is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc6", "question": "Who provoked controversy with the phone-sex conversation on her 1997 album \"The Velvet Rope\"?", "answer": "Janet Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f5", "question": "What animal has been called the \u201cpoor man\u2019s cow\u201d?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dad", "question": "Who performs the guest guitar solo on Michael Jackson's \"Beat It\"?", "answer": "Eddie Van Halen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa53", "question": "Which was the first suspension bridge over the River Thames in London?", "answer": "Hammersmith Bridge\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9b", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Rights of Man\"?", "answer": "Thomas Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acce", "question": "Who performed \"The Wall\" by the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Roger Waters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f5", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9b", "question": "On \"Cheers\", what was the name of the upscale seafood restaurant located directly above Cheers?", "answer": "Melville's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc6d76de0eb824d4052f9", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest living tree canopy, the size of three soccer fields?", "answer": "India -- A 550-year-old ficus benghalensis tree there, known as Thimmamma Marrimanu, has combined crowns that span 5.41 acres.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339679", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Homer's half brother?", "answer": "Herb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd22", "question": "According to Pliny the Elder, what word do we get from the Roman practice of paying soldiers in salt?", "answer": "Salary", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af67", "question": "Before being hanged, whose last words were \"I only regret that I have but one life to lose for my country\"?", "answer": "Nathan Hale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c4", "question": "What element has the chemical symbol Au?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a361", "question": "Where is the Abominable Snowman said to wander?", "answer": "The Himalayas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c9", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering nuclear fission?", "answer": "Otto Hahn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8a97d01dd7bf43be5e74e", "question": "In chess, the queen has the combined movement of which two pieces?", "answer": "Bishop and Rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba9", "question": "On the 1990's sitcom \"Roc\", what was Roc's job?", "answer": "Garbage man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a476", "question": "What African country was formerly known as Northern Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b767", "question": "What country traditionally goes last in the Olympic opening parade?", "answer": "The host country", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c6", "question": "Which state is home to Okefenokee National Wildlife Refuge?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc4206ce05a3942286f2d", "question": "What is the name of the ramrod in the television series \"Rawhide\"?", "answer": "Rowdy Yates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac52", "question": "What was the first animal sent up to outer space?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8a60ec223966ae8f8830", "question": "What is the only videogame franchise originating in the 1970's to have thus far generated over $1 billion in revenue?", "answer": "Space Invaders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f8", "question": "What song about her age did Charmain Carr sing in the movie version of \"The Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Sixteen Going on Seventeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae4", "question": "During World War II, what sex symbol was known as \"The Sweater Girl\"?", "answer": "Lana Turner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d9", "question": "In The Simpsons, what does the old Radioactive Man #1 comic smell like according to Milhouse?", "answer": "His grandfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6659fa5bfecdd737e0861", "question": "Who were the first people to use currency?", "answer": "Lydians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59d184923b17032616b590fa", "question": "The fisrt armed daylight bank robbery in the US is said to have occured in what year?", "answer": "1866", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51402ff04d658268c92e0", "question": "What Chinese princess commanded the \"Army of the Lady\"?", "answer": "Princess Pingyang,\u00a0the daughter of Emperor Gaozu of Tang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b108", "question": "What 1990's Russian president had quintuple bypass surgery while in office?", "answer": "Boris Yeltsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339faa", "question": "Who were Pete Cochran, Linc Hayes, and Julie Barnes?", "answer": "The Mod Squad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef0", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Willy Loman?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4da", "question": "Which is larger, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76673eec85e375820b280", "question": "Which two Great Lakes are connected by the Straits of Mackinac?", "answer": "Michigan and Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffcfbbd9dc5ec6cd98a8317", "question": "What painting is featured prominently in the 2007 film \"St Trinian's\"?", "answer": "Johannes Vermeer's\u00a0\"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339caa", "question": "What hero of 1926 played herself in the 1927 film \"Swim, Girl, Swim\"?", "answer": "Gertrude Ederle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d74", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"There and Back Again\"?", "answer": "The Hobbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caee", "question": "The process of making cows' milk safe for consumption is called what?", "answer": "Pasteurization", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c923", "question": "What nutrient is required by the body in order to build up muscles?", "answer": "Protein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e94a77ccba3ffe45786d6", "question": "What common term is used to describe a length of 9 inches?", "answer": "A span", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afb", "question": "What rock musician got his stage name from the yellow and black jerseys he used to wear?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2e", "question": "What book series was written and illustrated by Jeff Kinney?", "answer": "Diary of a Wimpy Kid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a56", "question": "What old TV puppet show was hosted by \"Buffalo\" Bob Smith?", "answer": "Howdy Doody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93c096bd93ce3a4e5f6a8", "question": "Which organ cannot feel pain?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015dedefe83fe1f2a824b73", "question": "How many people died in the Korean War?", "answer": "Two million", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7e6fff048f679a45ac0e", "question": "Bathmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Stairs or steep slopes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffac71cf6db9ac4808cf1", "question": "What country was the modern bicycle invented in?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9dc", "question": "Which fruit can restore your health in Donkey Kong 64?", "answer": "Watermelon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5bef6ce05a3942286e1b", "question": "Who directed the film \"Hacksaw Ridge\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b6", "question": "Which US state was boxer John L. Sullivan born in?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded0f3ea2747c8aff16d2e", "question": "What does the \"c\" in the equation \"e=mc2\" stand for?", "answer": "Speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbc942760f0007efaba0e5d", "question": "What does the abbreviation BC stand for?", "answer": "Before Christ", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca16", "question": "What joins muscles to bones?", "answer": "Tendons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a5d020565ad31a57c7d1", "question": "Seeds for what fruit were found in King Tut\u2019s tomb?", "answer": "Watermelon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe733a8eec85e375820b223", "question": "In a Nazi concentration camp, a black triangle identified a prisoner as what?", "answer": "Asocial", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601601b0fe83fe1f2a824c61", "question": "Many countries do not forthrightly recognize May Day but celebrate which other holiday in its stead?", "answer": "International Workers Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393de", "question": "In what year did Elton John release his single \"Crocodile Rock\"?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e63", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Mr. Magoo?", "answer": "Jim Backus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e8fdb24f84e0b9f9ffc7", "question": "What does the name Botswana mean?", "answer": "Land of the Tswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29f", "question": "Who said \"Too much of a good thing can be wonderful\"?", "answer": "Mae West", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2b", "question": "Who led his troops to disaster at the Little Bighorn in 1876?", "answer": "George Custer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab30", "question": "Which four independent countries does the region of Melanesia include?", "answer": "Vanuatu, Solomon Islands, Fiji, and Papa New Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe768c8eec85e375820b2a7", "question": "The Ghirardelli Chocolate Company was founded in which city?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cc", "question": "What two epic poems did the ancient Greek poet Homer write?", "answer": "The Iliad and The Odyssey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c76e877e98cb977789ce", "question": "Which continent is home to the only egg-laying mammals in the world?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae21", "question": "What is the famous brewery founded in Dublin in 1759?", "answer": "Guinness", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8a", "question": "What must be manufactured by Victorinox or Wenger to be official?", "answer": "Swiss Army knives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ed", "question": "What Harry Potter character has the patronus of a hare/bunny?", "answer": "Luna Lovegood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b62ce662d71a53651003", "question": "\"Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Isaac Newton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b918", "question": "From what animal do we get fleece?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76fd0eec85e375820b2f0", "question": "What's the largest freshwater lake in the world by surface area?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad7c", "question": "The Sphinx is a statue that guards what?", "answer": "Pyramids of Giza", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc1081469bb8041d07a06f", "question": "Which popular 1960's American car was affectionately known as \"The Goat\"?", "answer": "Pontiac GTO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af6", "question": "What TV science guy wore a red polka-dot bow tie on the box of his \"Way Cool Game of Science\" CD-ROM?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d60", "question": "Who is often considered the first to become a billionaire writing books?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c192", "question": "Which breed of dog gets its name from the Latin for earth?", "answer": "Terrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e90", "question": "What is the only signed work of Michelangelo?", "answer": "The Pieta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b2", "question": "In what modern-day country did the Sabines live?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56f", "question": "Which Australian animal has unique fingerprints?", "answer": "Koala", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aa4f20565ad31a57c815", "question": "The Anaconda Plan was associated to which war?", "answer": "The American Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b34b", "question": "Which Cambodian party was Pol Pot the leader of?", "answer": "Khmer Rouge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c426", "question": "What element is combined with iron to become steel?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad02", "question": "What company did Henry Ford found in 1899?", "answer": "The Detroit Automobile Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baca", "question": "On a medical diploma, what does D.D.S. stand for?", "answer": "Doctor of Dental Surgery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5d885dad637d903c8824", "question": "The southernmost city in the world is located in which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a8", "question": "What city is the setting for the Clint Eastwood movie \"Dirty Harry\"?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb0dc65ff7d326b622a64", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Pretzel Logic\"?", "answer": "Steely Dan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e9105bbd7247dfc0fa00314", "question": "What is the atomic number of the element Tantalum?", "answer": "73", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e14", "question": "George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\" is a roman \u00e0 clef for what historical event?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339735", "question": "In which decade was the first electric guitar made?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af78", "question": "Which US president is buried in Mount Vernon, Virginia?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff1411cb0ee8c595b6d39a0", "question": "Which famous mountain appears in \"Under the Great Wave off Kanagawa\"?", "answer": "Mount Fuji", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60172cff44491cbd7c5a177e", "question": "Who commanded the American troops during World War I?", "answer": "General John J. Pershing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c1", "question": "What beer is known as the \"champagne of beers\"?", "answer": "Miller High Life", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce1", "question": "The \"leap from the lion's head\" is the final challenge in what 1989 movie?", "answer": "Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b176", "question": "In what year did the State of California officially join the United States as its 31st state?", "answer": "1850", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0e", "question": "What literary character lived at 221B Baker Street?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77a", "question": "How many cards are there in the deck used to play the card game bezique?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993b", "question": "What character on the original Star Trek TV series was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59c1cde77bd84c0ea43ad431", "question": "In Norse mythology, what did Odin trade an eye for?", "answer": "Wisdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c86", "question": "Whose song \"Clubland\" begins his 1981 album \"Trust\"?", "answer": "Elvis Costello's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a8962404ad935a7e1a63f", "question": "Which Premier League team's mascot is the Red Devil?", "answer": "Manchester United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c651", "question": "How many daily tides are there?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65bfb1f3c0ead6880d60b", "question": "According to the Bible, where was Apollos from?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcd", "question": "What kind of tea takes its name from the Chinese for \"Black dragon\"?", "answer": "Oolong", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c94dfbde8045e48466ea", "question": "Why do pigs roll around in the mud?", "answer": "To cool down -- Pigs have very few sweat glands, so they must roll in mud to stay cool and prevent sunburns.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2122a31a458464a93c448", "question": "What Italian dessert literally translates to \"pick-me-up\"?", "answer": "Tiramisu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddd", "question": "Who reveals \"the man behind the curtain\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Toto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa56cec73aa70ea0b70b2d", "question": "Which two towns were destroyed and buried when Mount Vesuvius erupted in 79 A.D.?", "answer": "Pompeii and Herculaneum were both destroyed by the eruption in 79 A.D.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b167", "question": "What architect is largely credited with having designed Elizabeth Tower, also known as Big Ben?", "answer": "Augustus Pugin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ff43fe83fe1f2a824c4c", "question": "Why did US President Theodore Roosevelt ban Christmas trees in the White House in 1901?", "answer": "He banned the trees during his first year in office due to him being \"a devoted environmentalist\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989acb0cb8751d53e7d760c", "question": "Which two twin primes add up to 360?", "answer": "179 and 181", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a5ba90aac110e4167075", "question": "What does a Tegestologist collect?", "answer": "Beer coasters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6de", "question": "Liberty Island is located in the harbor of what US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Mr. Plow,\" who played Old Man Winter in Homer's Mr. Plow commercial?", "answer": "Grampa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a669", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Land of Enchantment\"?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c54e877e98cb977789ad", "question": "\"Blucifer\" is the nickname for which city's iconic horse statue?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b174", "question": "The US state of California was originally part of which Spanish territorial colony?", "answer": "New Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e9e838e4e5d4832e6312", "question": "In the \"Book of Judges\", Gideon stations his army on what mountain before attacking the Midianites?", "answer": "Mount Gilead", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb3", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bronx Cocktail?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4a", "question": "What is the last event in a decathlon?", "answer": "1500 Metres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a9", "question": "How did actor Humphrey Bogart die?", "answer": "Esophageal cancer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339163", "question": "Who created the cartoon TV show \"Futurama\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bf", "question": "What country is the setting for Shakespeare's Macbeth?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b3", "question": "The term Sesquincentennial represents how many years ?", "answer": "150", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339451", "question": "Who plays the role of Captain Jack Aubrey in the movie \"Master and Commander\"?", "answer": "Russell Crowe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd4607e83c707845b215b", "question": "What famous actor turned down the role of Trinity in film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Sandra Bullock turned down the role because she had the understanding that Will Smith was in the film.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac7", "question": "What sport is the subject of the book \"Sands of Time\"?", "answer": "Beach volleyball", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef59716ce05a3942286e03", "question": "How long was the sewer pipe that Andy crawled through to freedom in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "500 yards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c790", "question": "What color is the octopus blood?", "answer": "Light blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ea", "question": "Which 1985 song was co-written by Michael Jackson and Lionel Richie?", "answer": "We Are The World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f86", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in Children of a Lesser God?", "answer": "Marlee Matlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4288ff048f679a45ab79", "question": "What layer of the skin is just below the surface?", "answer": "Dermis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a552ee3e1c6f9840ba319e", "question": "On the 1976 release, who wanted to \"Fly Like an Eagle\"?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f4a8ff048f679a45aac8", "question": "Koumpounophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Buttons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392dc", "question": "What duo's debut album was titled \"Wednesday Morning, 3 AM\"?", "answer": "Simon & Garfunkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f1a701dd7bf43be5e806", "question": "What is the name of Niagara Falls' smallest waterfall?", "answer": "Bridal Veil Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecccbdec223966ae8f88a4", "question": "In what movie did Benedict Cumberbatch wear dentures that were an exact replica of Alan Turing's 60-year old set of false teeth?", "answer": "\"The Imitation Game\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf3", "question": "What medical term is used to describe the process of sweating?", "answer": "Hydrosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e52", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Old Yeller\"?", "answer": "Chuck Connors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a179", "question": "Which actor was \"The Postman\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a959d61d1b4d384d5d67b", "question": "\"White Room\" was a hit off which Cream album?", "answer": "Wheels of Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b991", "question": "Mean Joe Greene helped what team win four Super Bowls?", "answer": "Pittsburgh Steelers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933f", "question": "In what year did the TV show \"Grey's Anatomy\" premier?", "answer": "2005", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded1f4ea2747c8aff16d38", "question": "Laliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Speaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31a", "question": "Who provided the original voice for the character of Tigger?", "answer": "Paul Winchell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab6", "question": "Who wrote, TIdings of Comfort and Joy in 1997?", "answer": "T. Davis Bunn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99c7c21a8909e5c332d36", "question": "What type of insect is a \"weevil\"?", "answer": "A beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7a", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"A Little Less Conversation\" by Elvis Presley as its theme song?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a468", "question": "In which city would you find the Hermitage Museum?", "answer": "Saint Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe77630eec85e375820b318", "question": "What is the world's largest landlocked country?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26e", "question": "Who won an Oscar as Best Supporting actor in the 1993 film \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c477", "question": "What is cryogenics the study of?", "answer": "Production of low temperatures", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be19", "question": "What iconic Hawaiian object was based on the Portuguese braguinha?", "answer": "The ukulele", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339582", "question": "What movie takes place on February 2nd again and again?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Selma's Choice,\" Homer can't go to Duff Gardens because he's sick from eating what?", "answer": "An old, old sandwich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8f", "question": "Which stroke is swum first in a \"medley\" swimming event?", "answer": "Butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1b", "question": "What is the only New World member of OPEC?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "general"}]